You can't beat me.
（黛(まゆずみ)）
オマエじゃ オレに勝てねぇよ
I still consider myself the Phantom Sixth Man!
（黒子(くろこ)）幻のシックスマンという
呼び名—
まだ譲る気はありません！
（黛）はっ 上書きしたのか—
Did you overwrite
me?
オレに！
（赤司(あかし)）オマエの力は
まだ必要だ
We still need your strength.
I'm counting on you to help Rakuzan win.
洛山(らくざん)の勝利のために
期待しているよ
The ball disappeared...
（火神(かがみ)）ボールが消えた あっ！
（小金井(こがねい)）あっ！
（火神）今のはまさか!?
Was that...
（伊月(いづき)）ミスディレクション･
オーバーフロー!?
Misdirection Overflow?
No, it's a little different.
いいえ 少し違います
Mayuzumi-san's prone to
drawing attention right now.
黛さんは今 視線を
集めやすくなっている
そこに赤司君が—
Akashi-kun directed Kagami-kun's
attention to him.
火神君の視線を
誘導したんです
I'm Desperate
（根武谷(ねぶや)）しゃあ！
Yeah!
（木吉(きよし)）根武谷！
Nebuya!
へっ！ 止められるもんなら
止めてみろや 木吉！
Stop me if you can, Kiyoshi!
マッスルドリブル！
Muscle Dribble!
おおらああああ！
From Akashi's pass he's
pushing inside in a one-on-one.
（若松(わかまつ)）赤司のパスから
ワンオンワンに持ち込んで押し込む
力を見せつけてるみてーな
攻めだな
Rakuzan
Seirin
It's like he's showing off his strength.
（伊月）ハァ ハァ…
（木吉）くそっ
Damn it.
（笠松(かさまつ)）しかも 赤司の
黛の使い方は—
The way Akashi's treating Mayuzumi is
heartless.
非情—
There's no other word for it.
と言うほかないな
仕事は ただ火神の視界に
入る位置に突っ立ってるだけ
His job is simply to stand in
Kagami's field of vision.
Being treated that way must
be supremely galling.
そんな扱いは
この上なくショックなはずだ
The only reason he's doing it is because
それでも投げやりに
ならないのは—
ユニフォームを着て
コートに立ってるからだろう
he's wearing their uniform on the court.
The remaining shreds of his
sense of duty are the
かろうじて残っている
選手としての義務感だけが—
only thing forcing his body to move.
無感情に体を動かしている
（葉山(はやま)）あっ
（小金井）えい ふっ！
（ホイッスル）
（誠凛(せいりん)部員たち）よし！
Yeah!
Rakuzan
Seirin
They're back up to 20 points behind.
（笠松）20点差に戻したか
だが 洛山の攻撃を止めなきゃ—
But if they don't stop Rakuzan's attacks,
they won't close the gap.
差は縮まらねぇぞ
（福田(ふくだ)）くそぉっ
Damn it...
What can we do?
（降旗(ふりはた)）どうすれば…
Defense!
（土田(つちだ)）ディーフェンス！
Defense! Defense! Defense!
ディーフェンス！
（土田）洛山の攻撃は
五将の３人によるワンオンワン
Rakuzan is attacking with the
Uncrowned Kings' one-on-ones.
Defense! Defense! Defense!
ここから差を縮めるには—
To close the gap, the second-years
have to stop the Kings!
２年のオマエらが五将を
止めるしかないんだ！ 頼む！
Please!
ディーフェンス！
Tsuchida-senpai...
土田先輩
ディーフェンス！
うーわっ 盛り上がってくんねー
They're getting excited.
But...
けど まあ—
無理だけどね
It won't work.
I'm not feeling it, though.
（葉山）
正直燃えないけんども—
Kagami's all right, but this guy...
火神ならまだしも こいつじゃね
Can I ask you something?
１ついいかな？
What do you think of Mayuzumi?
黛のこと どう思ってる？
Nothing, really.
どうって 別に何も
We use him effectively to win.
勝つための
有効利用でしょ
何かダメ？
Is there something wrong with that?
I'm not complaining.
（伊月）
別に文句なんてないよ
I just
ただ—
don't want to lose.
負けたくもないな
ふーん あっそ
Really?
Three's probably enough,
（葉山）
たぶん３本で十分だろうけど—
but that annoyed me enough to use more!
今ウザかったから—
いっちゃうよ！
Four!
４本！
Hayama's Lightning Dribble!
（若松）
葉山のライトニングドリブル！
I can't pass him with four?
（葉山）４本でも抜けない!?
おっ イーグルアイで
全体の動きを見るから—
Is it harder to use speed
to mess with him because he
sees my entire body's
movements with Eagle Eye?
ドリブルスピードに
翻弄されにくいのか？
Your mentality has a big effect
on your performance.
（今吉(いまよし)）メンタルが
パフォーマンスに—
及ぼす影響は どでかい
A man's attitude can
change him dramatically.
心の持ち方ひとつで
人は驚くほど変わる
Somehow he's managed to
handle that monster.
（笠松）まがりなりにも—
ずっとあの怪物の
相手してたもんな
（伊月）ラクダが言いました
A camel told me.
Compared to Akashi,
you're barely a hump in the road.
赤司に比べりゃ—
よっぽど楽だ ってね
Yeah, nice.
キタコレ！
He likes it?!
（伊月）ウケた！
Sorry. Honestly, I underestimated you.
（葉山）いっやー マジごめん
はっきり言って ナメてたよ
おっけー
Okay.
Here comes five!
いくわ ５本！
Such power...
（伊月）なんて迫力…
Is this the true strength of the Kings?
これが五将の本気!?
なのに ヤバイ
But I've never felt anything like this.
こんなこと初めてだ
I'm scaring myself.
怖い
I'm frighteningly calm,
despite the situation.
このピンチで 自分でも
怖いくらい落ち着いてる
来る！
He's coming.
He passed him!
（若松）抜いた！
Eagle Spear!
（河原(かわはら)）イーグルスピア！
But that's not fast enough to reach him.
（実渕(みぶち)）間に合わないでしょ—
その程度じゃ
What? He's already on his second bounce?
（伊月）なっ もう２つ目に!?
It's no use! He's too fast!
ダメだ　ドリブルが速すぎる！
（木吉）うりゃー
Izuki...
（小金井）伊月
Sorry.
（伊月）悪い
No worries. Let's get them back.
（小金井）
ドンマイ 取り返そうぜ！
That's not what I meant.
（伊月）いや そのことじゃない
（小金井）え？
Huh?
I'm just glad I could do my best
against that monster.
（伊月）あんなとんでもない相手に
全力を出させたことが—
正直うれしくてさ
こんなときに ワクワクしてるんだ
I'm excited.
Izuki...
伊月…
葉山は任せてくれ
Let me handle Hayama.
絶対に何とかしてみせる
I promise I'll do something.
ハァ…
You caught Kagami's cooties.
火神菌 完全にうつってますよ
I don't like the sound of that!
その言い方は なんかヤダな
（葉山）
赤司 ボール送れ ガンガン！
Akashi, keep giving me the ball!
That's the plan.
そのつもりだ
だが つまらないミスなど
するなよ
But don't make any stupid mistakes.
'Course! I'm gonna crush them!
もち！
全力で ぶっ潰すしか
ないっしょ！
（ホイッスル）
（観客１）また きたぁー！
He made another basket!
Hayama's unstoppable!
葉山 止まらねー！
But he was watching.
けど今 見とったな
Instead of going for the Eagle Spear,
he watched him after he passed.
抜かれたあと イーグルスピアには
あえていかず—
観察しとった
Izuki-senpai...
伊月先輩
Kuroko,
黒子
大丈夫 もう一度だけ
やらせてくれ
I'm okay.
Let me do it one more time.
Next time
次は 止める！
I'll stop him.
おーっとおっと どうしても
オレを止めたいみたいね
Yeah, yeah.
You're determined to stop me.
But unfortunately, no matter what you do,
つってもまぁ 残念無念！
そんなのは どうあがいても—
you can't!
無理だけどねっ！
This is...
（葉山）これは!?
This is it! I will stop him!
（伊月）ここからが勝負
しとめる！
Kuroko!
（葉山）黒子!?
There's something I've realized
after letting him pass me.
（伊月）何度も抜かれて
分かったことがある
Hayama dribbles incredibly fast.
葉山のドリブルは
とてつもなく速い
But it places a heavy burden
on his receiving hand.
が それゆえに 受け止める手にも
相当な負荷がかかる
When he crosses back over,
he stiffens for a moment.
そこから もう一度
切り返すとき—
一瞬の硬直がある！
（葉山）
そんなこったろーと思ったよ
I was expecting this.
He dodged him!
（降旗）かわした！
He knew what was coming!
（福田）読まれてた
What? An Eagle Spear now?
（実渕）なっ ここで—
イーグルスピア！
（伊月）ダメだ！
やはり オレじゃこいつを…
It's no use! I can't stop him!
That should've been a blind spot!
死角だったはずなのに！
Hayama's instincts and reflexes
beat Izuki's far-reaching prediction!
先の先まで読んだ伊月を
葉山の野性と反射神経が超えた！
Hayama wins!
葉山の勝ちだ！
Are you sure you want to go there?
けど いいのか？
そこ—
猛獣危険の
立入禁止区域内だが
The Thunder Beast doesn't belong in there.
Crap!
（葉山）しまった
What?
なんだと!?
火神のブロック！
Kagami blocked him!
They stopped Rakuzan's attack!
（桜井(さくらい)）洛山の攻撃を止めた
（小金井）黒子！
Kuroko!
Koga, pass! Behind on your left!
（伊月）コガ パス！ 左後ろ！
Don't tell him!
もうっ バラさないでよ！
おわわっ あっぶねー！
That was close!
Go!
（福田）行っけぇ！
（河原）うっ 葉山が！
It's Hayama!
An alley-oop!
（赤司）アリウープか　チッ
おおおおーらぁ！
Rakuzan
Seirin
（歓声）
（降旗）火神のアリウープ！
Kagami's alley-oop!
That's one step forward!
（河原）一歩だけど 前進だ！
That's it!
（福田）いいぞぉー！
It's not just on defense. It's on offense, too.
（葉山）ディフェンスだけじゃない
オフェンスも—
He's using Eagle Eye to
understand the situation
イーグルアイで状況把握して—
and predict several moves into the future.
そっから何手先まで読んでんだよ
You've relaxed mentally,
but that doesn't make you any weaker.
いくら精神的に
ゆとりができたからって—
実力差が
ひっくり返ったりはしないさ
You're way stronger than me.
オレは オマエにはかなわない
けど それと止められるかどうかは
別の話だ
But that doesn't affect
my ability to stop you.
I'm glad you're not smarter than me.
オマエがオレより
賢くなくてよかったよ
SNAP
はい？
What?
おいっ 小太郎(こたろう) スローイン！
Kotaro, throw the ball in!
Five seconds!
（実渕）５秒！
Don't act so smug just
because you stopped me once!
（葉山）このやろう〜！
一度止めたくらいで
いい気になってんじゃねぇぞ！
Damn it!
このっ！
（黛）なっ
何オレにパスしてんだ バカ！
Why are you passing to me, idiot?
オレのマークが誰だか…
Do you know who's on me?
Crap!
（葉山）しまった
Rakuzan
Seirin
（歓声）
（河原）やったー！
Yes!
（降旗）連続得点だー！
Another basket!
っしゃあー！
Yeah!
Rakuzan
Seirin
Kuroko!
（葉山）このっ！
ちょっと！ 何ぼーっと
What are you—
Why is this happening?
（葉山）なんでこうなった！
スティールは頭に血が上ったせいだ
I let him steal the ball
because I was angry.
I was angry because Izuki provoked me.
頭に血が上ったのは
伊月に挑発されたせいだ
あんな挑発に乗っちまったのは—
I let him provoke me
because I underestimated him.
オレが あいつをナメてたからだ
Akashi.
（葉山）赤司
Sorry. I'd better avoid
one-on-ones for a while.
悪い この先しばらく
オレ １対１は控えるわ
I really want to get them back right away.
ホントは今すぐ
やり返したいとこだけど…
伊月は一流のプレーヤーだ
But Izuki's a first-rate player.
I can't charge in without thinking first.
考えなしに突っ込んだら
ヤバイ
（赤司）そうか
頭は冷えたようだね
Really? You seem to have calmed down.
That's good.
ならばいい
You're off the hook.
挽回まで大目に見よう
That was close.
命拾いしたわねぇ ホント
If you'd hadn't calmed
down, there's no telling
（実渕）もしムキになって
やり返そうとしてたら—
what would've happened to you.
アンタどうなってたか
分かんないわよ
Kagami's super wide range defense!
火神の超広域ディフェンス！
（火神）くそっ もっとだ
Damn it.
Focus. Focus more.
もっと集中しろ！
I feel like I'm sinking through
water when I enter the Zone.
ゾーンに入ると 水の中を
沈んでいくような感覚がある
The deeper I sink,
the sharper my skills get.
深く潜れば潜るほど—
自分が研ぎ澄まされていくのが
分かる
ゾーンには まだ先がある！
The Zone is deeper still.
（青峰(あおみね)）
バカヤロ火神！ これは—
You idiot, Kagami.
It's still not enough.
届いてねえ
Shit!
（火神）ヤベッ！
（赤司）ヌルい
Weak.
（ホイッスル）
（降旗）うぐっ！
You're so focused on the Zone,
you relaxed your guard against threes.
（赤司）
ゾーンを意識するあまり—
スリーへの警戒が甘くなったな
You must be unflinchingly prudent
細心の注意を払い
わずかでも緩めるな
if you want to stop me.
僕の動きを封じたければな
But it's only a matter of time.
とはいえそれも 時間の問題だがな
Even if you enter the Zone,
いくらゾーンに入って
くらいついたところで—
you'll run out of strength eventually.
じきに体力は底をつく
No worries, Kagami.
ドンマイ火神！ 取り返そう！
We'll get them back.
うっす
Yeah.
Go, Seirin! Go get 'em, Seirin!
（１年生たち）いけいけ誠凛！
おせおせ誠凛！
Rakuzan
Seirin
（歓声）
（土田）堅実に返した
We got them back, but...
けど…
We don't have any shooters.
（伊月）今 ウチには
シューターがいない
スリーを打つだけなら
火神 コガ オレにもできるが—
Kagami, Koga, and I can shoot threes.
成功率は
日向(ひゅうが)に遠く及ばない
But we've got nowhere near Hyuga's accuracy.
（木吉）洛山には赤司以上に
怖いシューターがいる
Rakuzan has scarier shooters than Akashi.
もしスリーを多用してこられたら…
If they start going for threes against us...
（火神）実渕！
Mibuchi!
（実渕）アタシは
小太郎みたいに—
Unlike Kotaro, I don't get
more or less excited
depending on who I'm facing.
相手によって
テンション コロコロ—
変わったりしないわよ
って
フンッ！
Why do you look so smug?
なんでアンタ
ちょっとドヤ顔なわけ？
なんでって—
Why? Because our team's Izuki
is freaking amazing!
“どーだ ウチの伊月は
すごいだろう”的な
What?
Huh? Wait, wait?
って え？ だってさ—
We're pressuring you guys
right now, right?
今おしてるのは
ウチじゃないの？
だからオレも頑張るぞ！
みたいな…
So, you know, I'd better
do my best, too.
（実渕）リアクションしづらい！
I don't know how to respond!
（実渕）うっ
いきなり豹変するわね
He changes at the drop of a hat!
天然!?
Is it natural?
Either way, he's a bit like Kotaro.
なんとなく
小太郎に似てるかも
カントク！
Coach...
Honestly, in terms of strength,
this might be the biggest mismatch.
正直 実力差は—
このマッチアップが一番
大きいかもしれないわね
Koganei-kun started playing in high school.
小金井君がバスケを
始めたのは高校から
But he's certifiably athletic
from his years on the tennis team.
けど それまでテニスで
培った運動神経は—
折り紙付きよ
It's the reason he's come this far
with no prior experience.
未経験者でここまで
きただけのものは持ってるわ
I don't have any experience
to predict what he'll do!
（小金井）
経験から予測するとか—
オレにはできない
All I can do is focus on
my opponent's movements!
だからとにかく—
相手の出方に全神経を
集中するしかない！
Is this...
（根武谷）まさかこれは！
Wild instincts?
（実渕）野性？
But it's only...
って レベル的には…
...at about that level.
（実渕）くらいの差はあるけど
（１年生たち）結構 薄め！
That's not much!
I could shoot a normal three.
（実渕）
普通のスリーでも勝負できる
けど 誠凛の子たちに
決して油断はしない
But I can't underestimate the Seirin boys.
I'll go with Earth.
ここは“地”のシュート
He took a step back?
（実渕）１歩下がった!?
“地”でくると読んだの？
Did he know I'd use Earth?
No, that's impossible!
まさか ありえないわ
でも 下がったのなら—
But since he stepped back,
it's easier to shoot Heaven!
“天”のシュートが
打ちやすくなっただけよ！
（小金井）てーぃ！
（実渕）うっ
（実渕）しまった
指がかかりすぎた！
Damn! I held the ball too long!
Hey!
（根武谷）オイ！
（ホイッスル）
（小金井）ううっ くっそー
Damn it!
（実渕）ネコはネコでも山ネコか
So he's more than just a house cat.
つくづく誠凛は一人残らず
油断ならないわね
We can't underestimate any of Seirin's players.
“地”から“天”への
切り替えに—
I can't believe he reacted when
I switched from Earth to Heaven.
反応してくるなんて
（木吉）ええい
（根武谷）ううー！
You can't keep making the same shots!
何度も同じパターンで
決めさせるかよ！
（木吉）ぐっ
（火神）先輩！
Senpai!
（ホイッスル）
（降旗）よっしゃ ナイス！
Nice!
Thanks, Kagami.
（木吉）助かったぜ 火神！
ウッス！
Sure thing.
This isn't good.
（リコ）マズい
黒子君のパスに
追いつかれるようになってきた
They're catching up to Kuroko-kun's passes.
シューター不在で ディフェンスを
広げられないんだわ
Without a shooter,
we can't spread their defense.
木吉
Kiyoshi...
ぶつかってくる気配
ゼロじゃねーか
You're not even trying to engage me.
You've become pretty meek.
ずいぶん おとなしく
なっちまったなぁ
Kiyoshi!
（小金井）木吉
顔 怖(こえ)えって！
You look terrifying.
ホラホラ 楽しんでこーぜ！
Come on. Let's have some fun.
別に そのセリフ
使うのはいいけど—
I don't mind you saying that,
but I feel like you're calming me down.
なんか あやされてる気分なんだが
Now, now.
You look like you're having fun, Koga.
楽しそうだな コガ
え？ そりゃあ—
Huh? Well, I'm not slacking. I'm desperate.
お気楽にやってる
わけじゃないし—
これでも必死だよ
But playing in a game is still fun.
けど 試合出て
プレーすんのは—
楽しいっしょ やっぱ！
It's incredible he even became decent
after starting in high school.
高校からバスケ始めて
並まで来たっつーのは—
ある意味すげーな あいつ
センスがあって
努力も相当したんでしょうね
He's got good instincts.
He probably practiced hard, too.
（今吉）褒めてるとこ悪いけど
問題は今どうかや
I hate to be a downer, but the
question is how good he is now.
An average player is
powerless against the Kings.
並じゃ 五将に歯は立たんで
そら 来たでぇ
Look. He's coming.
Mibuchi!
実渕！
Isn't he a sub for Seirin?
（観客１）
誠凛の あれは控え選手だろ？
（観客２）さっきのはマグレだろ
That must've been luck.
止められっこねーよ
He can't stop him.
They don't know anything.
Make them eat their words, Shinji.
（小金井の姉）
何も知らないヤツらに—
言いたい放題
言わせてんじゃないよ！
慎二(しんじ)
（小金井）ぐっ これは！
This is...
Even if you know what
this is, you can't stop it.
（実渕）今度のは
分かったところで—
何もできないわよ
A three without a fake?
ノーフェイクでスリー!?
いや これは…
No, this is...
（桜井）“虚空(こくう)”！
Void!
うっぐぅ…
（小金井の姉）
は？ バスケ部に入るぅ？
What? You're joining the basketball team?
What about tennis?
テニスは どーするのよ？
（小金井）やめる
I'm quitting.
It's not right for me.
オレには合ってなかったんだよっ
はー アンタねぇ—
You quit baseball, soccer, and swimming.
野球もやめ サッカーもやめ
水泳もやめ—
続いたもんが
１つもないじゃないのさ
You've never stuck with anything.
だから 合わなかったんだってばー
I told you, they weren't right for me.
There certainly is such
a thing as "the right fit."
（小金井の姉）あのね 慎二—
合う合わないは確かにある
But no sport is all fun at first.
けど 最初から
楽しいばっかの—
スポーツはないし—
There are things you won't realize
until you stick with something.
続けてみて
分かることだってあるんだよ
（小金井）続けてみて—
Things you realize by
sticking with something...
分かること…
I'm still not sure what it is,
but it's made me think...
まだピンとは
こなかったけど—
いろいろ思うようにはなった
最近バスケ楽しいかも とか—
That I've been enjoying basketball lately.
いろいろあったから—
That a lot has happened,
だから…
so I...
I want to win, no matter what!
何が何でも勝ちてー とか！
（葉山）レオ姉の“虚空”に
飛びついた!?
He jumped during Leo's Void?
（根武谷）
届きはしなかった が…
He didn't reach it, but...
落ちろー！
Fall!
Damn. I think I just
missed my only chance.
（小金井）ヤバイ オレ—
千載一遇のチャンスを逃したかも
次は もう“虚空”は…
On the next Void...
止められない そんな！
He can't stop it? No way!
Why?
なんで!?
During that shot, Mibuchi saw two truths.
今のシュートで
実渕は２つの事実を見たわ
１つは 小金井君が何らかの方法で
“虚空”の硬直から逃れたこと
First, that Koganei-kun
somehow moved during Void.
もう１つは—
Second,
that he still couldn't reach the ball.
それでも
届かなかったということ
次からは
小金井君が読んでも—
Even if Koganei-kun predicts it,
he'll calmly take the shot.
動揺せずに打ってくる
意表を突いたさっきが—
When he surprised him earlier,
that was his first and last chance.
最初で最後の
チャンスだったのよ
（日向）
最後なんかじゃねぇよ
It won't be the last.
Thanks to Koga, I know how
to stop his three pointers.
（日向）コガのおかげで
３種のシュートの攻略法…
そして 見切ったぜ—
And how to beat Void!
“虚空”！
Preview
（木吉）日向 出るのか？
Hyuga, you're going to play?
I know the risks, but it's not reckless.
（日向）リスクは承知だが—
ムチャとは思ってねえぞ
（木吉）ハハッ やっぱり
オマエにはかなわないな
I've got nothing on you.
Let Me Warn You
（日向）勝って笑って—
Let's win, laugh, and keep playing ball!
そんで この先も
バスケやろうぜ！
Yeah!
（木吉）おう！